Guide to the Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
- Series VII. Visual Material and Ephemera
  - Slides
    - Europe A reel 3, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Europe B reel 3 part 1, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Europe B reel 3 part 2 Spain and Portugal, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Europe B reel 4, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Europe B reel 5 (missing), 1963 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Asia trip reel 1, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Asia trip reel 2, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Asia trip reel 3, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Galapagos and Ecuador reel 1, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Galapagos reel 2, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Galapagos reel 3, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Galapagos reel 3.5, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Galapagos reel 4, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Seychelles, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Seychelles islands part 1, 1970-10-26-1970-11-12 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Seychelles islands part 2, 1970-10-26-1970-11-12 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Seychelles islands part 3, 1970-10-26-1970-11-12 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - This is Taiwan collection part 1, 1958-1964 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - This is Taiwan collection part 2, 1958-1964 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Portugal, Spain and Barcelona collection, 1963 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Europe, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Africa with Walter and Helen reel 1, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Africa reel 2, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Record sheet, Undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Parent's Asia trip return, Undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - LRS Galapagos, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Africa collection by Lester Hunter, Undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - LRS Asia, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Unmarked LRS Asia reel part 1, 1980 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Unmarked LRS Asia reel part 2, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Unknown slides, 1983-1984 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Assorted French slides, Undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Assorted marked, 1965-1969 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Uganda, Rhodesia, Umtata, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Galapagos and Panama Canal, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Eastern Asia collection, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Florida Audubon, Senior picnic, Sheldon and friends, 1953-03-1954 (Box 71, Folder 1)
      Stereo slides
    - Sheldon and friends, Florida, camp, Philadelphia zoo, 1953-1955 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Negatives
    - 35mm film negatives (Box 46-48)
    - Negatives (Box 52)
  - Ephemera
    - Ephemera (Box 62)
    - Ephemera (Map-case KK20, DD10)
    - Glass bird statuette, Undated; MU-1216 (Box 65)
- Series VIII. Audio and Audiovisual Materials
  Contains cassette and 8mm and 16mm reel audio/video takes of lectures, family events, bird calls, SLUR material, and Chinese language instruction and travel. Also two videocassettes.
  - Reel-to-reel tapes
    - Reel-to-reel tapes (Box 61)
    - LRS and Allison Schumann piano concerto, 1955-03-20; TR-17109 (Box 69)
  - Cassette tapes
    - Cassette tapes, including "Les' Tapes of Henry" (Box 61)
  - Video cassettes
    - Leslie Severinghaus video, V59
    - Tape of dinner held in honor of Leslie Severinghaus, V60
    - China tape 1, 1989; V-10653 (Box 69)
    - China tape 2, 1989; V-10654 (Box 69)
    - China tape 3, 1989; V-10655 (Box 69)
    - China tape 4, 1989; V-10656 (Box 69)
    - China tape 5, 1989; V-10657 (Box 69)
    - China tape 6, 1989; V-10658 (Box 69)
    - China, 1989; V-10659 (Box 69)
    - Where Confucius meets the New Wave, Undated; V-10660 (Box 69)
    - Creative spirits, Undated; V-10661 (Box 69)
      From Ou Cheng-Wei
    - To free an eagle, Undated; V-10662 (Box 69)
    - LRS Asian reading room Glee Club, 1990-05-25; V-10663 (Box 69)
      Alain Seznec, Frank Rhodes, Hank Luce
    - Beta part 1, Undated; V-10664 (Box 69)
    - Beta part 2, Undated; V-10665 (Box 69)
    - Beta part 3, Undated; V-10666 (Box 69)
    - Geographical fugue, Cornell glee club, Concert tour in Asia, 1989; V-10667 (Box 70)
    - Geographical fugue, Cornell glee club, Concert tour in Asia, 1989; V-10668 (Box 70)
    - Geographical fugue, Cornell glee club, Concert tour in Asia, 1989; V-10669 (Box 70)
    - Leslie Severinghaus, Undated; V-10670 (Box 70)
  - Film
    - Movies (Box 60-61)
    - Africa reel 1, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2072 (Box 69)
      8mm film (super 8)
    - Africa reel 2, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2073 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 3, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2074 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 4, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2075 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 5, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2076 (Box 69)
    - Discards Africa reel 1, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2077 (Box 69)
    - Discards Africa reel 2, 1968-01-22-1968-03-16; F-2078 (Box 69)
    - Galapagos reel 1, 1969-05; F-2079 (Box 69)
    - Galapagos reel 2, 1969-05; F-2080 (Box 69)
    - Galapagos reel 3, 1969-05; F-2081 (Box 69)
    - Discards Galapagos reel 1, 1969-05; F-2082 (Box 69)
    - Discards Galapagos reel 2, 1969-05; F-2083 (Box 69)
    - India reel 1, 1969; F-2084 (Box 69)
      LRS meets Sheldon and Lucia in New Delhi on their return from Taiwan; meetings of IUCN; France
    - India reel 2, 1969; F-2085 (Box 69)
    - Xmas, 1969-1970; F-2086 (Box 69)
    - Family continuation, 1970-1971; F-2087 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 1, 1971; F-2088 (Box 69)
      LRS, ELS, Walter, Helen
    - Africa reel 2, 1971; F-2089 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 3, 1971; F-2090 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 4, 1971; F-2091 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 5, 1971; F-2092 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 6, 1971; F-2093 (Box 69)
    - Africa reel 7, 1971; F-2094 (Box 69)
    - Sheldon and Lucia's wedding reel 1, 1968-07-20-1968-08; F-2095 (Box 69)
      Luces and Perkinses - Japan, Taiwan
    - Sheldon and Lucia's wedding reel 2, 1968-07-20-1968-08; F-2096 (Box 69)
    - Untitled reel, Undated; F-2097 (Box 69)
    - Untitled reel, Undated; F-2098 (Box 69)
    - Untitled reel, Undated; F-2099 (Box 69)
    - Untitled reel, Undated; F-2100 (Box 69)
    - Newfoundland and Nova Scotia, 1959; F-2101 (Box 70)
      16mm film
    - Europe, 1961; F-2102 (Box 70)
    - Florida, Cypress garden, 1953; F-2103 (Box 70)
    - Tinicum to Florida, 1956; F-2104 (Box 70)
    - Europe, 1963; F-2105 (Box 70)
    - Western trip, 1957; F-2106 (Box 70)
    - Florida, Matlavage, Elms, Thorington, 1952; F-2107 (Box 70)
    - Europe, 1956; F-2108 (Box 70)
    - Small bits for distribution, Summer 1957; F-2109 (Box 70)
      Enclosed list of small bits of miscellaneous film
    - Bird footage, 1962; F-2110 (Box 70)
    - Texas reel 1, 1958; F-2111 (Box 71)
    - Texas reel 2, 1958; F-2112 (Box 71)
    - Western trip, 1960; F-2113 (Box 71)
    - Children, 1934; F-2114 (Box 71)